[
  {
    "question": "Who was the Ulema member to issue Fatwa against Akbar from Jaunpur ?",
    "option_1": "Mulla Yazdi",
    "option_2": "Mirza Haqim",
    "option_3": "Abdun-nabi",
    "option_4": "Abdulla Sultanpuri",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements related to the mughal emperor Akbar and choose the correct answer: Statement I : 'Tansen' was the title given to Rambali Pandey by the Mughal emperor Akbar Statement II : Akbar was married with the sister of Raja Man Singh Statement III : Abul Fazl was the author of 'Ain-i-Akbari' Statement IV : Raja Todarmal was the commander-in-chief of Akbar's army",
    "option_1": "Only Statement I and II are correct",
    "option_2": "Only Statement III and IV are correct",
    "option_3": "Only Statement III is correct",
    "option_4": "Only Statement IV is correct",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who had caused the death of Abul Fazal?",
    "option_1": "Shahjada Salim",
    "option_2": "Abdur Rahim Khan-e-Khana",
    "option_3": "Shahjada Murad",
    "option_4": "Shahjada Daniyal",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Patron of Literature, Jahangir awarded the title of “Pandit Raj” to whom?",
    "option_1": "Munishwar Das",
    "option_2": "Bhagwati Swami",
    "option_3": "Jagannath",
    "option_4": "Raghunath",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who among the following had rebelled against Jahangir? 1. Ashaf Khan 2. Khurram 3. Mahabat Khan 4. Khusro",
    "option_1": "1 & 2 only",
    "option_2": "2 & 3 only",
    "option_3": "2 & 3 only",
    "option_4": "2, 3 & 4 only",
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following was the ambassador of British emperor James I in the court of Jahangir?",
    "option_1": "William Hawkins",
    "option_2": "William Finch",
    "option_3": "Petro Della Vella",
    "option_4": "Edward Terry",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The real name of Mumtaj Mahal was",
    "option_1": "Arzumand Bano Beghum",
    "option_2": "Ladli Beghum",
    "option_3": "Meharunnishan",
    "option_4": "Roshan Ara",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which of the following had Shahjahan honored as ‘Shah Buland Iquabal ?",
    "option_1": "Dara Shikoh",
    "option_2": "Shuza",
    "option_3": "Aurangzeb",
    "option_4": "Murad",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who had given famous Kohinoor Dimond to Shahjahan in gift?",
    "option_1": "Aurangzeb",
    "option_2": "Darashikoh",
    "option_3": "Mir Zumla",
    "option_4": "Abul Hasan Kutb Shah",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aamir who made significant reforms in land revenue system of Deccon during Shahjahan reign, was—",
    "option_1": "Ashaf Khan",
    "option_2": "Mahabat khan",
    "option_3": "Khan-e-jama",
    "option_4": "Murshid Kuli-Khan",
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who among the following was called as a 'Zindapir'?",
    "option_1": "Bahadur Singh 1",
    "option_2": "Shah Alam II",
    "option_3": "Aurangzeb",
    "option_4": "Adil Shah",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the chief Diwan of Aurangzeb?",
    "option_1": "Sadullah Khan",
    "option_2": "Afzal Khan",
    "option_3": "Asad Khan",
    "option_4": "Ismail Khan",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under which Emperor the number of Hindu commanders was maximum in Mughal army?",
    "option_1": "Humayun",
    "option_2": "Akbar",
    "option_3": "Jahangir",
    "option_4": "Aurangzeb",
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who had constructed the Babri Masque Situated in Ayodhya ?",
    "option_1": "Babur",
    "option_2": "Humayun",
    "option_3": "Nizam-ul-mulk",
    "option_4": "Mir Baki",
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jahangiri Palace is situated at-",
    "option_1": "Delhi",
    "option_2": "Aurangabad",
    "option_3": "Agra",
    "option_4": "Lahore",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements in reference to cultural history of India: 1. There is use of white marbles in Buland Darwaja and Khanqah located in Fatehpur Sikri 2. Red sand stone and marble was used in 'Bada Imambada' and 'Rumi Darwaja' located in Lucknow Which of the following statement is/are true?",
    "option_1": "Only 1",
    "option_2": "Only 2",
    "option_3": "Both 1 and 2",
    "option_4": "Neither 1 nor 2",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who built the Tomb of Etmauddaula?",
    "option_1": "Akbar",
    "option_2": "Noorjahan",
    "option_3": "Shahjahan",
    "option_4": "Aurangzeb",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Match the list I with list II and choose the correct answer from the codes given below:",
    "option_1": "a",
    "option_2": "b",
    "option_3": "c",
    "option_4": "d",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The famous tomb of Tansen is situated at-",
    "option_1": "Agra",
    "option_2": "Gwaliar",
    "option_3": "Jhansi",
    "option_4": "Jaipur",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which painter of Mughal period is called the ' Rafel of cast' ?",
    "option_1": "Jahangir",
    "option_2": "Basawan",
    "option_3": "Khwaja Abdus Samad",
    "option_4": "Vihzad",
    "answer": "4"
  }
]

